Preliminary Guide to the Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by Reynolds Price, 1954-2001 RL.00596
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by Reynolds Price
1954-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hunter, Jody Jones
RL.00596
21.7 Linear Feet
550 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Collection was received as a gift from Hunter in 1999, 2001, and 2008-2009.
Biographical Note
Hunter is a collector of works by certain southern authors taught by William Blackburn. Reynolds Price is creator of fiction, poetry, essays, plays, memoirs, Biblical translations, and drawings among other things. He is the James B. Duke Professor of English at Duke University, Durham, NC, where he has taught since 1958.
Collection Overview
This collection documents Price's career as a prolific and versatile author. Items include his works of fiction, books containing his contributions, books containing printed encomia, books entirely about Price, books and periodicals containing interviews with and/or articles about Price, books and periodicals formerly owned by Price, audio and video recordings, typescripts, letters, postcards, self-portraits, and photographs.
The addition (2001-0057) (90 items, 1.7 linear feet; dated 1955-2001) consists largely of books and printed material either written by or containing reference to or contributions from Price. Also includes his professional and personal correspondence, 1962-1990; a printer's proof, with editing marks, of Clear Pictures: First Loves, First Guides (1989); the original typescript of his senior honors thesis on John Milton (1955); and five self-portraits in various media.
Addition (2008-0082) (3 items, 2 lin. ft.; dated 1998 and undated) comprises one poster and two black-and-white photographs of Price. One photograph features Price and William Styron.
American literature -- 20th century; Authors, American -- 20th century; Literature -- History and criticism; American literature -- Southern States; Authors, American -- Southern States; Self-portraits; Milton, John, 1608-1674; Hunter, Jody Jones; Hunter, Jody Jones; Price, Reynolds, 1933-2011
- Accession (1999-0273)
  Scope and Contents note
  [Unwrap books and copy newsprint before patron use.]
  - Kate Vaiden (Box 1)
  - Use of Fire (Box 1)
  - Clear Pictures (Box 1)
  - Love and Work (Box 1)
  - Mustian (Box 2)
  - Pylon (Box 2)
  - Wings of the Dove (Box 2)
  - Christ Haunted Landscape (Box 2)
  - First Person Singular (Box 2)
  - In Praise.....Essays (Box 2)
  - Discovering North Carolina (Box 2)
  - Understanding North Carolina (Box 2)
  - My Silk Purse (Box 2)
  - You Can't Eat Magnolias (Box 2)
  - Winter's Tale (Box 2)
  - Writer's Dreams (Box 2)
  - Best American Short Stories 1964, 1975, 1992 (HB and PB) (Box 2)
  - O Henry Prize 1961 (Box 2)
  - Selected Stories: So. Rev. (Box 2)
  - To Be..... (Box 2)
  - Separate Country (Box 2)
  - Writer's Harvest (Box 3)
  - For the Love of Books (Box 3)
  - 1967 Chanticleer (Box 3)
  - Images of Southern Writers (?) (Box 3)
  - Songs in the Rough (Box 3)
  - Limited Editions:
    - E. Welty, Form of Thanks (Box 3)
    - Back Before Day (Box 3)
    - Real Copies (Box 3)
    - Presence and Absence (Box 3)
    - Home M.... (Box 3)
    - Nine Mysteries (Box 3)
    - A Start (Box 3)
    - House Snake (Box 3)
    - Final Letter (Box 3)
    - Mark as Story (Box 3)
    - Good News: Mark (Box 3)
    - Palpable God (Box 3)
    - Letter to a Man in the Fire (Box 3)
    - Honest Act: Mem. Life (Box 3)
    - Incarnation (Box 3)
    - Three Gospels (Box 3)
    - Lord John Signatures (Box 3)
  - Books from the personal library of Reynolds Price (Box 4)
  - Five Reynolds Price videos (Box 4)
  - Red Clay Reader, volumes 1-7 (Box 5)
  - Magazines (Box 5)
  - Two Price bibliographies (Box 6)
  - One and Twenty (Box 6)
  - 2 on William Blackburn (Box 6)
  - Understanding Reynolds Price (Box 6)
  - A Long and Happy Life (Box 6)
  - Learning a Trade (Box 6)
  - Roxanna Slade (Box 6)
  - Laws of Ice (Box 6)
  - Eudora Welty (Box 6)
  - Untouchable Clouds (Preface by Price) (Box 6)
  - Early Christmas (Box 6)
  - A Whole New Life (Box 6)
  - Borrowed Time (Box 6)
  - Collected Stories (Box 7)
  - Blue Calhoun (Box 7)
  - Foreseeable Future (Box 7)
  - New Music (Box 7)
  - Full Moon (Box 7)
  - Good Hearts (Box 7)
  - Common Room (Box 7)
  - New Music (Box 7)
  - Tongues of Angels (Box 7)
  - Good Hearts (Box 7)
  - Unlabeled books from same original box as those in box 9 (Box 8)
  - Modern American Memoirs (Box 9)
  - Afterwards (Box 9)
  - Conv.-R.P. (Box 9)
  - Higher Pl... (Box 9)
  - Song of Solomon (Box 9)
  - Chapel Hill Carousel (Box 9)
  - Stories-Mod. So. (Box 9)
  - Anthologies (Box 9)
  - Literary Magazines (Box 9)
  - Promise of Rest (Box 10)
  - Source of Light (Box 10)
  - Vital Provisions (Box 10)
  - Private Contentment (Box 10)
  - Permanent Error (Box 10)
  - 3 James Taylor CDs (Box 10)
  - 2 Audiotapes (Box 10)
  - 3 Plays: Horton Foote (Box 10)
  - For Aaron Copland (Box 11)
  - Robert Penn Warren (Box 11)
  - Early Dark ( Photocopy of printer's typescript) (Box 11)
  - A Palpable God (Typescript) (Box 11)
  - Bear Pond (Box 11)
  - Esquire (3 issues) (Box 11)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous papers (Box 11)
  - Nine Mysteries (Box 11)
  - For Reynolds Price (2) (Box 11)
  - The Lines of Life (Box 11)
  - Country Mouse, City Mouse (Box 11)
  - Other small vol. limited editions (Box 11)
  - Southern Writers (Box 11)
  - Articles by and about Price (Box 11)
  - RANAM (Box 11)
  - The Surface of Earth ( Uncorrected Proof) (Box 12)
  - Good Hearts ( Typescript) (Box 12)
  - Names and Faces of Heroes (Box 12)
  - Articles by and about Price (Box 12)
  - Les Noms et Visages de Héros (Box 12)
  - A Chain of Love (Box 12)
  - The Young Writer at Chapel Hill (Box 12)
  - Lesson Learned (Box 12)
  - Torso of an Archaic Apollo (Box 12)
  - Other small vol. limited editions (Box 12)
  - Wings of Dove (Typescript?) (Box 13)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous papers (Box 13)
  - Southern Nights Chapbook Series (Box 13)
  - Book Reviews and other articles (Box 14)
  - Book Reviews and other articles (Box 15)
  - Framed self-portrait (Box 16)
  - Framed photograph (autographed by Price) (Box 16)
  - Broadsides (Box 16)
  - Self-portraits (Box 16)
  - Oversized broadside (Box 16)
  - Broadside- Poem (Box 16)
  - Dead Man, Dying Girl- Poem (Box 16)
  - Full Moon broadside (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Program (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Newsletter (Oversize-folder 1)
- Accession (2001-0057)
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - A Perfect Friend (Box 1)
    - Three Minutes or Less: Life Lessons from America's Greatest Writers, PEN/Faulkner Foundation (Box 1)
    - Eudora Welty: Writers' Reflections upon First Reading Welty, ed. Pearl McHaney (Box 1)
    - Feasting the Heart (Box 1)
    - The Calling, Sterling Watson, uncorrected proofs [includes note about book by Price] (Box 1)
    - Letters to a Fiction Writer, ed. Frederick Busch (Box 1)
    - Mean Time, Christopher T. Leland (Box 1)
    - Chestnut Mare, Beware, Jody Jaffe (Box 1)
    - The Scribner Sampler, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Cathedrals of Kudzu: A Personal Landscape of the South, ed. Hal Crowther (Box 1)
    - A Singular Family: Rosacoke and Her Kin (Box 1)
    - The Best Spiritual Writing, 1998, ed. Philip Zaleski (Box 1)
    - But Now I See: The White Southern Racial Conversion Narrative, Fred Hobson (Box 1)
    - The Calling, Sterling Watson, signed by the author (Box 1)
    - Southern Dogs and Their People, P. S. Davis and Roberta Gamble (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - The Southern Review, Spring 2000 (Box 2)
    - Academic Eye: Reynolds Price Collects Danny Robinette, program for exhibit at Duke University Museum of Art (Box 2)
    - The Best American Poetry 1998, ed. John Hollander (Box 2)
    - A Single but Huge Distinction (Box 2)
    - A Gracious Plenty: Recipes and Recollections from the American South, John T. Edge (Box 2)
    - Feasting the Heart, advanced uncorrected proofs (Box 2)
    - The Georgia Review, Fall 1993 and Spring 1999 issues (Box 2)
    - Crux: The Letters of James Dickey, ed. Matthew Bruccoli and Judith S. Baughman (Box 2)
    - A Portrait of Southern Writers: Photographs by Curt Richter, signed by the photographer (Box 2)
    - Loose material, including periodicals, programs, clippings, and poems by Price (Box 2)
    - Clear Pictures: First Loves, First Guides, typescript (first printer's proof), with editing marks (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Reynolds Price Letters, 1969-1990 (Box 3)
      Includes correspondence from Price to various recipients.
    - John Milton: The First Forty Years; A Study in Motivation, 13 April 1955, [original copy of Price's senior honors thesis for Duke University] (Box 3)
    - Untitled binder containing business correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 3)
    - Letters to Stuart Wright, 1977-1987 (Box 3)
    - About Town magazine, February 1962 (Box 3)
      Contains an article about Price (Accession 2009-0071).
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Five self-portraits in various media, including 2 labelled "College days" (Box 4)